elated.com 2019-05-09

# Privacy Policy | Matt Doyle | Elated Communications

## Who we are

We are Matthew Doyle t/a Elated Communications, a registered business in Australia. Our Australian Business Number is 77 346 357 526. Our website address is: https://www.elated.com .

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

If you send us a message via our contact form at https://www.elated.com/contact/, your name, email address, message subject and message body will be sent to us via email. This information is necessary so that we can contact you about your message. The information you enter via the contact form is not stored on our server.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics to track visits and interactions on our website. To do this, Google Analytics saves several cookies and also collects your IP address. To find out more about how Google Analytics obtains and uses data about your visits to our site, see <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>.

## Who we share your data with

If you use our website then your personal information may be shared with the following entities:

  * **Google Analytics:** For the purposes of tracking visits (see  _Analytics_ above).
  *  **Mailchimp:** If you sign up for any of our mailing lists then we may share your first name and email address with Mailchimp for the purposes of sending you marketing emails. To find out how Mailchimp handles your information, see Mailchimp’s privacy policy at <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

If you send us an email via any of our contact forms then we may retain the email indefinitely.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

If you sign up for one of our mailing lists then your first name and email address is sent to Mailchimp, a United States company. Mailchimp participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. For more information, see MailChimp’s privacy policy at <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/> .

## Our contact information

If you have any privacy-specific concerns about your use of this website, please contact us at <https://www.elated.com/contact/>.
